<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-05-29T19:34:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>SNCF and NUMA - Collaborate with an ecosystem and build win-win relationships</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/sncf-and-numa-collaborate-with-an-ecosystem-and-build-win-win-relationships/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/sncf-and-numa-collaborate-with-an-ecosystem-and-build-win-win-relationships/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T19:34:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T19:34:46+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>SANOFI and NUMA - Deepdive in our ecosystem</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/sanofi-and-numa-deepdive-in-our-ecosystem/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/sanofi-and-numa-deepdive-in-our-ecosystem/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T19:25:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T19:32:02+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="sanofi" src="/images/cover_sanofi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p class="lead"&gt;Corporate strategy managers, in charge of innovation at Sanofi, envision to raise awareness among their team on the digital market, venture capitalism approach and lean methodology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;ACTION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with our partner, we build a one day immersive session.
–a first module to “unfold” their minds through presentations and sharing on initiatives from our network. These talks were lead by various profils - mentors, entrepreneurs and investor.
–a second module including a workshop on lean product development. Participants worked on a business problem and went throughout the 3 key concepts: hypothesis approval, MVP and test/iteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;IMPACT&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently discussing a long term partnership with Sanofi to train and support their teams in developing new product &amp;amp; services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation is about failure, iteration, dedication and desire&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Use case approach allowed to share a lot with my coworker that I did not know”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Innovation is about failure, iteration, dedication and desire”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathieu Giraud - Senior Corporate Strategy Project Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="fluid second"&gt;
	&lt;div class="mask"&gt;
		&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I_TmfbKI1Ig" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Total and NUMA Shift the way to work and gain quick-wins</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/total-and-numa-shift-the-way-to-work-and-gain-quick-wins/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/total-and-numa-shift-the-way-to-work-and-gain-quick-wins/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T19:13:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T19:22:26+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="Fiodor and Claudio" src="/images/clau_fiodor.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IT department came in with 2 teams to work on 2 different problems:
–a lack of understanding internally on the role and functions of the IT department;
–design a process that will allow identification and management of IT projects off the usual track and collaborating with an external ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;ACTION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Program was run in 2 steps in October 2014:
–train the team through hands on workshops on lean product development;
–accelerate the projects applying lean approach including user research to challenge assumptions and prototypes and allow tests and iterations.
Each team was responsible for its own solution and supported by a team of entrepreneur-mentor. Occasionally experts from our network (UX designer, developer, etc.) would join the teams to recreate conditions of a design studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Les équipes n’étaient pas en concurrence, chacune responsable d’un projet, elles étaient accompagnées par un mentor-entrepreneur et, ponctuellement, par des experts (UX designer, développeur, etc.) de notre réseau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;IMPACT&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both prototypes are under development for implementation and this program will be renewed in 2015. Total also thinks of new externalised format programs to lead at NUMA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The result of this program was amazing because the work of these two teams will be directly usable, and also because of the method that NUMA taught us. Everything that was told to us during the program made me realize the relevance of working closely with startups and use startups method.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yves-André Valot, CIO at TOTAL Marketing &amp;amp; Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Le Gouvernement et NUMA Faire la preuve de l’open data</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/le-gouvernement-et-numa-faire-la-preuve-de-l-open-data/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/le-gouvernement-et-numa-faire-la-preuve-de-l-open-data/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T18:48:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T19:07:16+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="gov_img" src="/images/gov_img.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Le Ministère du travail travaille au positionnement de Pole Emploi comme acteur majeur de la formation et de l’emploi.
Dans cette optique, une des pistes à explorer consiste dans l’ouverture de l’accès aux datas dont disposent Pole Emploi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;ACTION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En collaboration avec les services du cabinet et de la DSI du ministère, nous avons conçu un programme sur 2 mois d’open innovation visant à faire naitre des collaborations entre les institutions publiques - Pole Emploi, INSEE, DARES - et des privés, startups ou intermédiaires.
Le programme consistait en :
-une première phase préalable d’analyse des enjeux et d’identification des acteurs via une série d’entretiens ;
-une seconde phase de travail via 3 ateliers d’ideation et de conception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;IMPACT&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aujourd’hui le ministère du travail et des partenaires européens discutent pour monter et financer le développement de 4 prototypes autour de projets tels que :
-une cartographie des sociocompétences - en remplacement du CV traditionnel
-un outil d’aide à la définition d’un parcours de formation
-et un outil d’assistance au pilotage d’un recrutement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ce qui a changé dans le rapport de mes équipes à la question du numérique c’est qu’on est passé d’une forme de désintérêt du type “il se passe quelque chose dans le milieu numérique” mais ça ne me touche pas, à un vrai questionnement qui est de se dire : qu’est-ce que l’on pourrait en faire si tout ça arrivait chez nous. Comment est-ce qu’on se pose des questions différentes et comment est-ce qu’on veut y apporter des solutions différentes. Et une fois qu’on a passer ça oui, on trouve les moyens technologiques de le faire. C’est donc un sujet profond de culture.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;François-Xavier Petit&lt;/strong&gt; - Conseiller Numérique, innovation et prospective
Ministère de l’emploi, du travail, et de la formation professionnelle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="fluid second"&gt;
	&lt;div class="mask"&gt;
		&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I_TmfbKI1Ig" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Qunb simplifie la lisibilite de vos donnees</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/qunb-simplifie-la-lisibilite-de-vos-donnees/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/qunb-simplifie-la-lisibilite-de-vos-donnees/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T17:49:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T18:45:46+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="cover_qunb" src="/images/cover_qunb.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.qunb.com/"&gt;QunB&lt;/a&gt; qui est passé par &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.numa.paris/Sprint"&gt;NUMA Sprint&lt;/a&gt; (le Camping saison 2) propose une solution de datavisualisation à partir d’outils tels que Google Insights et Google Analytics. Objectif : rendre toute cette quantité de données plus lisible. En pratique, les données brutes sont ainsi extraites des documents mis à leur disposition, analysées de façon sémantique et retraitées automatiquement sous forme de graphiques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QunB a remporté en 2012 la Startup Competition à LeWeb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Après avoir suivi le programme d’accélération du camping, puis celui de Techstars, la start-up a été rachetée en novembre 2014 par Ve Interactive, pour plusieurs millions d’euros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pour en savoir plus:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/06/data-visualisation-startup-qunb-wins-leweb-paris-2012-startup-competition/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Techcrunch" src="/images/tc-techcrunch.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.veinteractive.com/press/20141128/ve-acquires-qunb-multi-million-pound-deal-expand-big-data-analytics-offering"&gt;veinteractive.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Natha Sorin Richez</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/natha-sorin-richez/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/natha-sorin-richez/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T01:12:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T13:36:10+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Parce que c’est à tous que nous permettons de prendre part !&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
