<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-05-29T17:49:00+02:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Qunb simplifie la lisibilite de vos donnees</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/qunb-simplifie-la-lisibilite-de-vos-donnees/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/qunb-simplifie-la-lisibilite-de-vos-donnees/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T17:49:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T18:45:46+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="cover_qunb" src="/images/cover_qunb.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.qunb.com/"&gt;QunB&lt;/a&gt; qui est passé par &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.numa.paris/Sprint"&gt;NUMA Sprint&lt;/a&gt; (le Camping saison 2) propose une solution de datavisualisation à partir d’outils tels que Google Insights et Google Analytics. Objectif : rendre toute cette quantité de données plus lisible. En pratique, les données brutes sont ainsi extraites des documents mis à leur disposition, analysées de façon sémantique et retraitées automatiquement sous forme de graphiques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QunB a remporté en 2012 la Startup Competition à LeWeb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Après avoir suivi le programme d’accélération du camping, puis celui de Techstars, la start-up a été rachetée en novembre 2014 par Ve Interactive, pour plusieurs millions d’euros.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pour en savoir plus:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/12/06/data-visualisation-startup-qunb-wins-leweb-paris-2012-startup-competition/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Techcrunch" src="/images/tc-techcrunch.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.veinteractive.com/press/20141128/ve-acquires-qunb-multi-million-pound-deal-expand-big-data-analytics-offering"&gt;veinteractive.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Natha Sorin Richez</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/natha-sorin-richez/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/natha-sorin-richez/</id>
    <published>2015-05-29T01:12:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T13:36:10+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Parce que c’est à tous que nous permettons de prendre part !&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Amorcer le changement par l’immersion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/amorcer-le-changement-par-l-immersion/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/amorcer-le-changement-par-l-immersion/</id>
    <published>2015-05-26T17:11:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T18:25:04+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="fluid second"&gt;
	&lt;div class="mask"&gt;
		&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/I_TmfbKI1Ig" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;AMBITION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p class="lead"&gt;Les responsables de la stratégie au niveau du groupe Sanofi, en charge de l’innovation, souhaitaient sensibiliser leur équipe aux enjeux de l’économie numérique et à l’approche Lean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sanofi" class="img-responsive" src="/images/cover_sanofi.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;ACTION&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;En collaboration, nous avons monté une journée d’immersion autour de :
–modules de présentations et d’échanges sur des initiatives de notre réseau - mentor, startup, investisseur ;
–ainsi qu’un atelier sur le Lean amenant les participants à travailler en équipe pour appliquer l’approche sur une problématique concrète. Ces ateliers portaient sur la compréhension et l’application de 3 concepts clés : formalisation et validation des hypothèses, définition d’un Minimum Viable Product et principe du test et itération.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 class="sm-head"&gt;IMPACT&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nous discutons aujourd’hui avec la direction de la Stratégie d’une approche globale d’accompagnement et de formation de leurs équipes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“L’innovation ce sont des échecs, de l’itération, de la persévérance et de l’envie.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“J’ai apprécié l’approche cas pratique qui a permis de mieux échanger avec des collègues que je ne connaissais pas.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mathieu Giraud - Senior Corporate Strategy Project Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>La seule startup francaise rachetee par Twitter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/la-seule-startup-francaise-rachetee-par-twitter/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/la-seule-startup-francaise-rachetee-par-twitter/</id>
    <published>2015-05-26T16:43:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T13:36:10+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="sketchfab" src="/images/team-mesagraph.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avec une technologie publicitaire basée sur l’analyse de hashtag, Mesagraph a su éveiller l’intérêt de Twitter qui, en 2014, a racheté la start-up française soit 2 ans et demi après sa sortie du programme &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.numa.paris/Sprint"&gt;NUMA Sprint&lt;/a&gt; (le Camping saison 1) !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NUMA est l’environnement le plus propice au développement des idées et à leur validation. Dans un délai très court, nous avons pu définir les meilleures orientations pour Mesagraph et créer les conditions de notre succès&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sebastien Lefebvre, CEO de Mesagraph&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/03/31/twitter-buys-frances-mesagraph-to-ramp-up-social-tv-work-in-euroupe/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Techcrunch" src="/images/tc-techcrunch.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.lesechos.fr/01/04/2014/lesechos.fr/0203414485997_twitter-s-offre-la-start-up-francaise-mesagraph.htm"&gt;&lt;img alt="Les Echos" src="/images/les_echos.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NUMA at the Digital Youth Summit in Peshawar aspiration and innovation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/numa-at-the-digital-youth-summit-in-peshawar-aspiration-and-innovation/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/numa-at-the-digital-youth-summit-in-peshawar-aspiration-and-innovation/</id>
    <published>2015-05-22T18:48:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T13:36:10+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class="cover"&gt;&lt;img alt="Digital Youth Summit2015" src="/images/digitalyouthsummit2015.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="lead"&gt;“What am I doing on this plane? I mean, WHAT THE HELL AM I DOING ON THIS PLANE?!” I ask myself the same question every time, whether I’m on my way to Algiers, Dakar, Bethlehem, Cairo or Beirut.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, it’s &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.google.fr/maps/place/Peshawar,+Pakistan/@28.8956567,75.4686928,4z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x38d917b90f0e79cf:0xa816b2637558a412"&gt;Peshawar&lt;/a&gt; Yes, you heard me, Peshawar, the city that is known for being on the Afghan border, for being the biggest city on the cusp of the “tribal zones”, for its fatal terrorist attacks and its religious zealots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the 6th until the 8th of May, it is this very location hosting the &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.digitalyouthsummit.pk/"&gt;Digital Youth Summit&lt;/a&gt;, the biggest event dedicated to new technologies and the youth of today in Pakistan. Last year, for its first instalment, there were a little over 500 people in attendance, this year over a thousand are expected. In all, three days full of conferences and panels on issues revolving around innovation. This event is organized by Basecamp, the first co-working space in Peshawar, and the World Bank (with whom we’ve already had the pleasure of collaborating), and supported by big companies such as Nestlé and Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What strikes me first is the &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt;! The &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt; that the people feel just to be together, the joy of being there, the joy of meeting each other and getting to know each other again. Even surrounded by armed soldiers, even in the most dangerous city in Pakistan, even despite the obvious threats, this joy to be a part of a community and to remind yourself that it is possible – possible to change the image that everyone has of them, possible to create startups here, and to succeed in a country gripped by terrorism and religious zealotry, possible to contribute to change within this society. What I notice next is the sheer diversity seen in the room – there are so many women present, many more than is seen in startup events in France. And here they are, these wonderful women, their faces expressing concentration, consideration and conviction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s the thirst for knowledge, the conferences and the panels are sold out, the speakers are surrounded by youngsters, brimming with questions, thirsty for knowledge and experience. The experience I’m talking about is one that I want to share with them, no templates to be followed, no best practices, no magic formulas, just a story that embodies the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the content of these three days, you might think you were at a miniature version of &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.futur-en-seine.paris/"&gt;futur en seine&lt;/a&gt;! With conferences, panels, lightning talks with no equivalent in European or American festivals: a conference on the Future of Work, a panel entitled “From an Idea to the Market” to which I had the pleasure of contributing, another on Government 2.0, pitches from startups in front of a hotbed of investors and even a round-table discussion on &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://fashiontechweek.fr/"&gt;Fashion Tech&lt;/a&gt;, a subject that we touched upon recently here at NUMA. Add this to the workshops on the Maker Movement, on the Architecture of Information and the Blog Monetization, what you’ve got is a rich and lively festival, and one that often reflected those seen in Western countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the conferences, what struck me the most were the projects that I discovered there! Emerging startups with real services to offer and outstanding scalability potential. I refer here to &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://robohealth.pk/"&gt;Robohealth&lt;/a&gt;, the winner of the pitching competition, a startup that aims to digitalize hospitals and clinics throughout Pakistan. Also there was &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://smilesn.com/"&gt;Smile&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile-based social network available offline, which means users can stay in touch with comments and updates via SMS. Lastly, &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.emperorsbazaar.com/"&gt;Emperor’s Bazaar&lt;/a&gt;, an e-commerce site that promotes and sells products created by Pakistani craftspeople. These are but a small taste of all those that I managed to meet, Pakistani soil is so very rich, with the launch of a new special investment fund announced during the Summit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My greatest encounter, however, was perhaps with Hasseb Awan, a young Pakistani serial entrepreneur, notable co-founder of &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.bitaccess.co/"&gt;Bitaccess&lt;/a&gt;, a startup accelerated by Ycombinator in 2014 and which aims to become the first ever decentralized bank. This guy is a true entrepreneur with multiple exits, real vision and real business nous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told myself that, if with the current infrastructure, such incredible projects are already being developed, what might it be like once NUMA arrives on the scene? We will be able to identify these kinds of entrepreneurs with great potential, then support, develop and accelerate these brilliant startups. With an international network of locations, we can make their upscaling easy and allow them to conquer new markets. What we can do is show that innovating in emerging countries is, indeed, possible and that the projects being developed there can be as good as those accelerated in Europe, and that the startups developed there can even tackle some markets that our own startups often neglect – emerging countries. In short, there is some seriously remarkable innovation and business potential there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yes, to finish up, why the hell am I on that plane each time? Because I know that it is in these places that we are at our most useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful in terms of being able to promote emerging ecosystems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful in terms of being able to share our experience in structuring and developing ecosystems, which often resemble that of Paris, circa 2008.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful in terms of promoting an alternative to the Silicon Valley model, one that focuses on open-mindedness, cooperation, diversity and performance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful in terms of opening branches of NUMA with local actors in order to identify the stars of tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Useful in terms of bringing them into an international network of locations which will allow them to upscale quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, it is with this ambition that we have decided to develop our own company, by developing on the international stage and launching the operation &lt;a target="_blank" href="http://yeswecrowd.co/"&gt;yeswecrowd.co&lt;/a&gt;! We firmly believe that it is in these emerging ecosystems that we will find the startups of tomorrow; that it is working with these kinds of countries that we will open up new markets; that it is in Morocco, South Africa, India and South America that we will find new drivers for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the future is there, and there’s no time to lose!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;YESWECROWD!&lt;/h4&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>DocTrackr l’exit à dix millions de dollars</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/doctrackr-l-exit-a-dix-millions-de-dollars/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/doctrackr-l-exit-a-dix-millions-de-dollars/</id>
    <published>2015-05-22T18:27:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-05-29T13:36:10+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.intralinks.com/platform-solutions/platform/information-rights-management"&gt;DocTrackr&lt;/a&gt; aide les entreprises à garder leurs documents en sécurité et sous contrôle qu’importe où ils soient stockés et avec qui ils sont partagés.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Après un passage par &lt;a href="http://en.numa.paris/Sprint"&gt;NUMA Sprint&lt;/a&gt; (le Camping saison 1), puis chez TechStars, DocTrackr se fait ensuite racheter par le géant américain &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.intralinks.com/"&gt;Intralinks&lt;/a&gt; pour 10 millions de dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="docktrackr" src="/images/image_doctrackr.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Simplement, avant le Camping, il n’y avait pas de DockTrackr et en l’espace de 3 mois, on a appris à passer d’une idée à un projet, et dans un second temps de 3 mois, d’un projet à une entreprise. 6 mois plus tard, on levait 2 millions auprès de 2 des meilleurs Business Angels parisiens, embauchait 19 personnes et gagnait de gros clients internationaux comme Aerospacial US”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Pour en savoir plus:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/24/intralinks-acquires-document-security-service-doctrackr/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Techcrunch" src="/images/tc-techcrunch.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
